Guide to the South Africa Now Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Interviews, 1978-1991, undated; Series V
  - Tapes F736-F737: Dean Farisani (Human Rights Watch), 1989 December 8; 2 (Box 1191–1192)
  - Tape F738: Thabo Mbeki; Jay Naidoo; Paris Interviews, 1989 December 4; 1 (Box 1193)
  - Tapes F739-F740: Kenneth Kaunda, 1989 December 11; 2 (Box 1194–1195)
  - Tapes F741-F742: Gay McDougal, 1989 November 30; 2 (Box 1196–1197)
    See also tapes F287-F288, boxes 770-771, F523-F525, boxes 994-996, and F977, box 1398.
  - Tapes F743-F744: Alexander Cockburn, 1989 November 29; 2 (Box 1198–1199)
  - Tape F745: Barbara Masekela, 1989 December 4; 1 (Box 1200)
  - Tapes F745-F746: Steven Swetewa, 1989 December 4; 2 (Box 1200–1201)
    Tape F745 (box 1200) contains frequent noise interference.
  - Tapes F747-F748: Michael Clough, 1989 December 8; 2 (Box 1202–1203)
  - Tapes F749-F750: Mark Gevisser, Undated; 2 (Box 1204–1205)
  - Tape F751: Max Coleman, 1989 December 12; 1 (Box 1206)
  - Tapes F751-F752: Jay Naidoo, 1989 December 12; 2 (Box 1206–1207)
  - Tapes F752: David Dinkins at United Nations, 1989 December 12; 1 (Box 1207)
  - Paris Conference
    - Tape F753: Isabelle Marque (French journalist); Rick Naidoo (Conference remarks); Chris Louw (Afrikaans journalist) -- Tape 1 of 4, Undated; 1 (Box 1208)
    - Tape F754: Chris Louw (continued); Jeannette Minnie -- Tape 2 of 4, Undated; 1 (Box 1209)
    - Tape F755: Jeannette Minnie (continued); Ricky Naidoo -- Tape 3 of 4, Undated; 1 (Box 1210)
    - Tape F756: Ricky Naidoo (continued); FAWU (Food and Allied Worker's Union) spokesman -- Tape 4 of 4, Undated; 1 (Box 1211)
  - Tapes F757-F758: Jane Hunter, Undated; 2 (Box 1212–1213)
  - Tapes F759-F761: Dr. Motlana and Kaiser Foundation, 1989 December 14; 3 (Box 1214–1216)
  - Tape F762: Archbishop Tutu at United Nations Plaza, 1990 January 2; 1 (Box 1217)
  - Tapes F763-F764: Theo Ben Gurirab, Namibian Minister of ForeignAffairs, 1989 November 24; 2 (Box 1218–1219)
  - Tapes F765-F767: Ralston Deffenbaugh, Director Lutheran Office for World Community, 1989 January 5; 3 (Box 1220–1222)
    F767 includes exterior shots of Steven Wise Synagogue.
  - Tape F768: Howard Wolpe; George McGovern; Gloer Butcher (Interviews, D.C.), 1989 November 17; 1 (Box 1223)
  - Tape F769: Mr. H. Asheeke of South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO), 1989 August 10; 1 (Box 1224)
  - Tape F770: Horst Kleinschmidt, International Defence and Aid Fund (IDAF), 1990 January 10; 1 (Box 1225)
  - Tape F771: Archbishop Trevor Huddleston, 1990 January 10; 1 (Box 1226)
  - Tapes F772-F773: Rian Malan, 1990 January 10; 2 (Box 1227–1228)
  - Tapes F774-F776: African National Congress (ANC) press conference: Reverend Huddleston, 1990 January 9; 3 (Box 1229–1231)
  - Tape F777: David Dinkins at City Hall, 1990 January 11; 1 (Box 1232)
  - Tapes F778-F779: Sathima Bea Benjamin, 1990 January 12; 2 (Box 1233–1234)
  - Tapes F780-F781: Peter Katjavivi, Namibian Constitutional Assembly, 1990 January 16; 2 (Box 1235–1236)
  - Tape F782: Peter Magubane, 1990 January 19; 1 (Box 1237)
  - Tapes F783-F784: King Leka, 1990 January 19; 2 (Box 1238–1239)
  - Tapes F785-F787: Huge Masekela, 1989 November 21; 3 (Box 1240–1242)
  - Tape F788: Ricardo Alarcon (segments include Cuban troops pull-out), 1990 January 29; 1 (Box 1243)
  - Tape F790: Mr. Count Pietersen, Deputy Chief Representative, Pan Africanist Congress (PAC), 1990 February 2; 1 (Box 1244)
  - Tapes F791-F792: Mathilda Krim: AIDS in South Africa, 1990 February 6; 2 (Box 1245–1246)
  - Tapes F794-F796: George Bizos, 1990 February 8; 3 (Box 1247–1249)
    The same tape number was assigned to two different recordings (F796).
  - Tapes F796-F798: Columbia University Conference on Namibia, interviews with H. Asheeke and Robert Parito, 1990 February 10; 3 (Box 1250–1252)
  - Tape F799: Themba Vilikazi, African National Congress (ANC) Chief Representative, 1990 February 9; 1 (Box 1253)
  - Tapes F800-F801: Mark Swilling, 1990 February 8; 2 (Box 1254–1255)
  - Tapes F802-F804: Jeremy Shearer, South African Ambassador, 1990 February 9; 3 (Box 1256–1258)
  - Tape F805: Peter Mokaba, Undated; 1 (Box 1259)
  - Tape F806: Patrick "Terror" Lekota (audio), 1990 February 8; 1 (Box 1260)
  - Tape F807: Ambassador Jeremy Shearer, 1990 February 10; 1 (Box 1261)
  - Tape F808: Mark Swilling, analysis of Mandela speech, 1990 February 12; 1 (Box 1262)
  - Tape F809: Betty Raptopoulos (New York Stock Exchange [NYSE] metals expert), 1990 February 14; 1 (Box 1263)
  - Tapes F810-F811: Press conference with Angolan representative to the United Nations (UN), 1990 February 8; 2 (Box 1264–1265)
  - Tapes F812-F813: Bill Minter, 1990 January 31; 2 (Box 1266–1267)
  - Tape F814: Jaielo Muekalia, 1990 February 1; 1 (Box 1268)
  - Tapes F815-F817: Postcards -- Janet Gaynor, artist, [No year] February 23; 3 (Box 1269–1271)
  - Tapes F817-F819: Sindiwe Magona, [No year] February 23; 3 (Box 1271–1273)
  - Tapes F821-F822: Jacques Pauw, 1990 February 27; 2 (Box 1274–1275)
  - Tapes F823-F824: Laurie Garrett, 1990 March 1; 2 (Box 1276–1277)
  - Tapes F825-F826: Micheala Clayton, 1990 March 1; 2 (Box 1278–1279)
  - Tapes F850-F851: Themba Mhambi, 1990 March 2; 2 (Box 1280–1281)
  - Tapes F851-F852: Oswald Mtshali, 1990 April 4; 2 (Box 1281–1282)
  - Tape F855: Molefe Tsele, Undated; 1 (Box 1283)
  - Tape F865: Stanley Mabizela, Undated; 1 (Box 1284)
  - Tape F866: Lindiwe Mabuza, Undated; 1 (Box 1285)
  - Tape F867: Dr. Gerrit van Viljoen, Undated; 1 (Box 1286)
  - Tape F868: Angolan Minister van Dunem press conference, 1990 April 25; 1 (Box 1287)
  - Tapes F869-F872: Ben Magubane, 1990 April 27; 4 (Box 1288–1291)
  - Tapes F873-F875: Joseph Oesi, Undated; 3 (Box 1292–1294)
  - Tape F876: Hidipo Hamutenya, Minister of Information for Namibia; Dr. Zed Ngarive, Director of Namibia Development Commission, 1990 April 27; 1 (Box 1295)
  - Tapes F877-F878: Mark Gevisser, critic [Re: The Gods Must Be Crazy II ], 1990 April 24; 2 (Box 1296–1297)
  - Tapes F879-F880: Mahlatini and the Mahotella Queens and West Nkosi, 1990 April 19; 2 (Box 1298–1299)
  - Tape F881: Get Ahead interview, 1990 April 5; 1 (Box 1300)
  - Tapes F882-F883: Ambassdor Pedro Commissario Afonso, Mozambique Ambassador to United Nations (UN), 1990 May 4; 2 (Box 1301–1302)
  - Tapes F884-F887: Father S. Khatshwa and Professor Charles Villa-Vincencio, Institute for Contextual Theology [re: religion and negotiations]; Nomvula Monkonyane [re: labor domestics]; Fr. Albert Dolan, 1990 May 8; 4 (Box 1303–1306)
  - Tapes F888-F889: Allister Sparks, 1990 May 9; 2 (Box 1307–1308)
  - Tapes F890-F891: Anthony Lewis, 1990 May 15; 2 (Box 1309–1310)
  - Tapes F892-F893: Joseph Shabalala of Ladysmith Black Mambazo, 1990 May 15; 2 (Box 1311–1312)
  - Tapes F894-895: Myrtle Witbooi -- South African Domestic and Allied Workers Union, 1990 May 18; 2 (Box 1313–1314)
  - Tapess F897-F899: Mandela, breakfast meeting, 1990 May 14; 3 (Box 1315–1317)
  - Tapes F900-F901: Pete Rosenblum -- Lawyer's Commission, 1990 June 1; 2 (Box 1318–1319)
  - Tape F902: Michael Edward Stevens [re: Freedom Charter], 1990 June 7; 1 (Box 1320)
  - Tape F902: Rob Jones, Africa Fund, 1990 May 25; 1 (Box 1321)
  - Tape F903: Jim Bell -- Mandela reception, 1990 June 7; 1 (Box 1322)
  - Tape F904: Reverse Angles of Phillip (Jim Bell interview), 1990 June 7; 1 (Box 1323)
  - Tapes F907-F908: Nicholas Hayson, human rights lawyer and Willie Madisha, Congress of South African Trade Unions (COSATU) representative, 1990 May 30; 2 (Box 1324–1325)
  - Tapes F909-F910: Elisa Harris, Brookings Institution [re: biological warfare], 1990 April 4; 2 (Box 1326–1327)
  - Tape F911: Jeremy Rifkin [re: biological warfare], 1990 April 4; 1 (Box 1328)
  - Tape F912: Makau wa Matua, Lawyer's Committee for Human Rights, 1990 June 8; 1 (Box 1329)
  - Tapes F913-F915: Dan Mafole, re: State of Emergency, 1990 June 8; 3 (Box 1330–1332)
  - Tapes F916-F917: Wall St. -- Mandela's visit; Bell's office, 1990 June 11; 2 (Box 1333–1334)
  - Tapes F918-F921: Cuban Ambassador to United Nations (UN), 1990 June 11; 4 (Box 1335–1338)
  - Tapes F922-F923: Richard Knight of the Africa Fund, New York City re: sanctions, 1990 June 11; 2 (Box 1339–1340)
  - Tape F924: Reverend Lucus, 1990 June 11; 1 (Box 1341)
  - Tapes F925-F926: Mandela Reception Committee Break Meeting -- interviews with Arthur Ashe, Harry Belafonte, Mother Moore, Aruba Ben Rahad, 1990 June 15; 2 (Box 1342–1343)
  - Tape F927: First Boston, interview with Phillip, 1990 June 15; 1 (Box 1344)
  - Tape F928: Dr. Sam Nujoma Nauru, President of Namibia, 1990 June 22; 1 (Box 1345)
  - Tapea F929a-F929b: Okey Ndibe and Usman A. Wai, 1990 June 27; 2 (Box 1346–1347)
  - Tape F930: Duncan Sellars, International Freedom Foundation, Undated; 1 (Box 1348)
  - Tape F931: The African National Congress (ANC) Speaks Out: A Conversation with Father Gqiba, Chaplain of the African National Congress (ANC), 1990; 1 (Box 1349)
  - Tape F932: J. B. Stephans, U.S. Attorney for Washington, D.C., 1990 February 1; 1 (Box 1350)
  - Tape F933: Fernando Nimo, Mozambique, 1990 July 13; 1 (Box 1351)
  - Tapes F934-F935: Religious Action Network (R.A.N.), Dr. Walker and Canon Williams, 1990 July 16; 2 (Box 1352–1353)
    The same tape number was assigned to two different recordings (F935).
  - Tape F935: Jim Donahue, 1990 January 31; 1 (Box 1354)
    See also: Tape F938.
  - Tape F937: David Dinkins press conference, Undated; 1 (Box 1355)
  - Tape F938: Jim Donahue [re: multinational monitor], 1990 January 31; 1 (Box 1356)
  - Tapes F939-F940: Mozambican Ambassador, 1990 January 31; 2 (Box 1357–1358)
  - Tapes F941-F942: Jay Feldman, national coordinator, National Coalition Against the Misuse of Pesticides (NCAMP), 1990 February 1; 2 (Box 1359–1360)
  - Tape F943: Lyndall Mafole (African National Congress [ANC]), 1990 February 8; 1 (Box 1361)
  - Tape F944: Violet Gwangwa (African National Congress [ANC]) on youth conference at M.S.U., 1990 February 8; 1 (Box 1362)
  - Tapes F945-F947: Elombe Brath [re: Pan Africanist Congress (PAC)], Undated; 3 (Box 1363–1365)
  - Tapes F948-F949: Dr. Betty Shabazz, Undated; 2 (Box 1366–1367)
  - Tapes F950-F951: Pule Pule [re: Azanian Peoples Organization], 1990 August 22; 2 (Box 1368–1369)
  - Tapes F952-F954: Gail Gerhardt; Peter Molotsi, 1990 August 23; 3 (Box 1370–1372)
  - Tapes F955-F956: Michael Gefford, Undated; 2 (Box 1373–1374)
  - Tape F957: Graca Michel, Undated; 1 (Box 1375)
  - Tape F958: A deputy of the Broadcasting Company re: TV in Namibia, 1990 August [31]; 1 (Box 1376)
  - Tape F959: Michael Kennedy [re: Angola USA Chamber of Commerce], 1990 August 30; 1 (Box 1377)
    The audio on the tape weakens and fluctuates after approximately three mintes of content.
  - Tapes F960-F961: Frank Fredricks (Namibian runner), 1990 September 5; 2 (Box 1378–1379)
  - Thandeka Gqubule (first black anchor)
    See also: Tapes F1035-F1036, boxes 1461-1462.
    - Tapes F962-F963, 1990 September 8; 2 (Box 1380–1381)
    - Tapes F962-F963, 1990 September 15; 2 (Box 1382–1383)
  - Tapes F964-965: Jim Casen, American Committee on Africa (ACOA), 1990 September 9; 2 (Box 1384–1385)
  - Tape F966a-F966b: Sheila Sisulu [re: education], 1990 September; 2 (Box 1386–1387)
  - Tapes F967-F969: Joel Carlson, 1990 September 20; 3 (Box 1388–1390)
  - Tape F970: Bob Joffee, Lawyers Committee, 1990 September 20; 1 (Box 1391)
  - Tape F971: Nomazizi Sokudele, 1990 September 20; 1 (Box 1392)
  - Tape F972: Graham Boynton, 1990 September 21; 1 (Box 1393)
  - Tapes F973-F974: Stix Mabuse, 1990 August 14; 2 (Box 1394–1395)
  - Tape F975: Desmond Tutu, 1990 September 27; 1 (Box 1396)
  - Tape F976: Damu Smith, Undated; 1 (Box 1397)
  - Tape F977: Gay McDougal, 1990 September 24; 1 (Box 1398)
    See also: tapes F287-F288, boxes 770-771, F523-F525, boxes 994-996, and F741-F742, boxes 1196-1197.
  - Tape F978: Sam Nujoma, 1990 September 29; 1 (Box 1399)
  - Tape F979: Anver Versi, Undated; 1 (Box 1400)
    The audio on tape is weak and distorted.
  - Tapes F980-F981: Cas Coovadia, Undated; 2 (Box 1401–1402)
  - Tape F982: Cyril Ramaphosa, General Secretary, National Union Mine Workers, Undated; 1 (Box 1403)
  - Tape F983: Jackie Cilliers, 1990 September 28; 1 (Box 1404)
  - Tape F984-F986: Patrick "Terror" Lekota, [No year] September 28; 3 (Box 1405–1407)
    The same tape number was assigned to two different recordings (F986).
  - Tapes F986-F987: Brenda Fasie, 1990 October 5; 2 (Box 1408–1409)
  - Tapes F988-F989: Moses Mayekiso, 1990 October 12; 2 (Box 1410–1411)
  - Tape F990: Fragment of Joe Slovo interview (less than three minutes), Undated; 1 (Box 1412)
    There is a note on tape cassette that "this is not Tape 990 Joe Slovo interview."
  - Tapes F990-F991: Joe Slovo, 1990 October 12; 2 (Box 1413–1414)
    The same tape number was assigned to two different recordings (F990).
    Tape F991 (box 1414) contains no audio during the last few minutes of content.
  - Tape F992: Allan Boesak, 1990 October; 1 (Box 1415)
  - Tape F993: Damu Smith, Undated; 1 (Box 1416)
  - Tape F994: Mr. Count Pietersen, 1990 August 10; 1 (Box 1417)
  - Tape F995: Jackie Selebi, Undated; 1 (Box 1418)
  - Tape F996: U.S. Democratic Representative Dymally, 1990 October 16; 1 (Box 1419)
  - Tape F997: Allan Boesak, 1990 October; 1 (Box 1420)
  - Tapes F997-F998: Joseph Labonte, American Business Initiative for a Free South Africa (ABIFSA), 1990 October 16; 2 (Box 1420–1421)
  - Tapes F999-F1000: Damu Smith -- consultant for Angolan government aid to União Nacional para a Independência Total de Angola (UNITA), 1990 October 18; 2 (Box 1422–1423)
    UNITA is known in English as National Union for the Total Independence of Angola.
  - Tape F1001: Slovo; Clough, 1990 October 19; 1 (Box 1424)
  - Tape F1002: Mitch Synder, 1990 October 19; 1 (Box 1425)
  - Tape F1003: Mandela's Release; Rob Jones, 1990 January 16; 1 (Box 1426)
  - Tape F1004: Dan Mafole re: Conservative Party, 1990 October 5; 1 (Box 1427)
  - Tape F1005: Conservative Party and Democratic Party, 1990 October 5; 1 (Box 1428)
  - Tapes F1006-1007: Abel Chivukuvuku, União Nacional para a Independência Total de Angola (UNITA) representative, 1990 October 26; 2 (Box 1429–1430)
  - Tape F1008: Patrick "Terror" Lekota interview, 1990 October; 1 (Box 1431)
  - Tape F1009: Gillian Slovo, 1990 June 26; 1 (Box 1432)
  - Tape F1010: Ian Smith on "McLaughlin", 1990 July 11; 1 (Box 1433)
  - Tapes F1011-F1012: Sister Bernard, 1990 November 4; 2 (Box 1434–1435)
  - Tapes F1013-F1014: Julie Frederickse [re: non-racialism], Undated; 2 (Box 1436–1437)
    The same tape number was assigned to three different recordings (F1014).
  - Tape F1014: Mervyn Dymally interview, 1990 January 30; 1 (Box 1438)
  - Tape F1014: Modesi, 1990 November 19; 1 (Box 1439)
  - Tapes F1015-F1016: Adam Hochshild, 1990 November; 2 (Box 1440–1441)
  - Tapes F1017-F1018: Stephen Ellmann, law professor, 1990 nov 15; 2 (Box 1442–1443)
    The same tape number was assigned to two different recordings (F1018).
  - Tape F1018: Interview with Roy Laishley, managing editor of Africa Recovery, 1990 November 20; 1 (Box 1444)
  - Tape F1019: Adotei Akwei [re: Harms Commission findings; hit squads], 1990 November 16; 1 (Box 1445)
  - Tapes F1020-F1021: Sister Bernard Ncube, Undated; 2 (Box 1446–1447)
  - Tapes F1022: Raymond Enriques (Henriques), Undated; 1 (Box 1448)
    See also: Tape F1062.
  - Tapes F1023-F1024: Steve Tshwete, National Organizer and National Executive Committee -- African National Congress (ANC), Undated; 2 (Box 1449–1450)
  - Tape F1025: Mel Hollan, Information Officer NECC (National Education Crisis Committee), Undated; 1 (Box 1451)
  - Tape F1026: Max du Preez; Danny Schechter, 1990 December 3; 1 (Box 1452)
  - Tapes F1027-F1029: Tom Karis, professor, City University of New York (CUNY), Undated; 3 (Box 1453–1455)
  - Tape F1030: John Copelyn, General Secretary, Southern African Clothing and Textile Workers' Union (SACTWU), 1990 December 18; 1 (Box 1456)
  - Tape F1031: Jerry Herman; Dumisani Kumalo; Tom Lodge, 1990 December 18; 1 (Box 1457)
  - Tapes F1032-F1035: Nomazizi Sokudele, 1990 September 19; 4 (Box 1458–1461)
  - Tapes F1035-F1036: Thandeka Ggubule, 1990 September 19; 2 (Box 1461–1462)
    See also: Tapes F962-F963, boxes 1380-1383.
  - TapeF1037: The Death Throes of Apartheid interview with Jim Wesley, Undated; 1 (Box 1463)
  - Tape F1038: Ms. Jappi, Southern African Clothing and Textile Workers' Union (SACTWU) Education Officer, 1990 September 29; 1 (Box 1464)
  - Tape F1039: Albert Peters, United Nations (UN) High Commission on Refugees, 1991 January 4; 1 (Box 1465)
  - TapeF1040: Michael Posner, lawyer on Committee for International Bill of Human Rights, 1991 January 3; 1 (Box 1466)
  - Tapes F1041-F1043: Rap Session: South African students, 1991 January 8; 3 (Box 1467–1469)
  - Tape F1044: Tom Hazlett, economist, 1991 January; 1 (Box 1470)
  - Tape F1045: Richard Knight [re: "one man one shore"], 1991 January; 1 (Box 1471)
  - Tape F1046: Anthony Marx, 1991 January 14; 1 (Box 1472)
  - Tapes F1047-F1048: Ian Steadman, theatre professor, Witwatersrand University, 1991 January; 2 (Box 1473–1474)
  - Tape F1049: David Smuts, Director of Legal Assistance, Namibian human rights lawyer, 1990 December; 1 (Box 1475)
  - Tapes F1050-F1051: Murphy Marobe, 1991 January 30; 2 (Box 1476–1477)
  - Tapes F1052-F1053: Tom Karis, Undated; 2 (Box 1478–1479)
  - Tapes F1053-F1054: Binifer Narozi, Undated; 2 (Box 1479–1480)
  - Tapes F1055-F1056: General Bantu Holomisa, Undated; 2 (Box 1481–1482)
  - Tape F1059: Roy Laishley -- Africa Recovery, 1991 February 7; 1 (Box 1483)
  - Tapes F1060-F1061: Lulu (Oxfam), 1991 February 7; 2 (Box 1484–1485)
  - Tape F1062: Raymond Henriques (Enriques), Undated; 1 (Box 1486)
    See also: Tape F1022.
  - Tapes F1062-F1063: Stuart Conn, playwright -- "By the Pool", 1991 February 15; 2 (Box 1487–1488)
    The same tape number was assigned to two different recordings (F1062).
  - Tape F1064: Adotei Akwei [re: sanctions], 1991 February 17; 1 (Box 1489)
  - Tape F1065: Mike Fleshman -- American Committee on Africa (ACOA), 1991 February; 1 (Box 1490)
  - Tapes F1065-F1066: Bill Schapp, "He's of Our Times", 1991 February; 2 (Box 1490–1491)
  - Tape F1067: Richard Knight [re: diamond sanctions]; Wren on Buthelezi piece, Undated; 1 (Box 1492)
  - Tape F1068: Namibian Church Leaders, 1989 June 22; 1 (Box 1493)
  - Tape F1069: Henry Hampton and others [re: Black journalists' media coverage], 1989 August 18; 1 (Box 1494)
  - Tape F1070: Nun -- eye-witness to student massacre in Zaire, Flemish, 1990 June 1; 1 (Box 1495)
    Title on case, "Mobutu," is incorrect.
  - Tape F1071: Diallo of UNICEF (The United Nations Children's Fund) [re: media coverage of South Africa], Undated; 1 (Box 1496)
  - Death Penalty
    - Tape F1072: Paula McBride; Peter Mothle, 1990 March 21; 1 (Box 1497)
    - Tape F1073: Peter Mothle; Colleen Bradley; Lucrecia Seefeld (sp?) -- human rights lawyers, 1991 March 21; 1 (Box 1498)
  - Tapes F1074-F1075: Nomegcobo Sangweni and others, Undated; 2 (Box 1499–1500)
  - Tape F1077: Michael Posner, Undated; 1 (Box 1501)
  - Tape F1078: Hugh Masekela and Dawn [Zane?], Undated; 1 (Box 1502)
  - Tapes F1079-F1080: "Mango Groove", Undated; 2 (Box 1503–1504)
  - Tape F1081: Ruth Tomaselli on SABC (South African Broadcasting Corporation), 1989 December 8; 1 (Box 1505)
  - Tape F1082: Chris Hani, African National Congress (ANC), 1991 April 18; 1 (Box 1506)
  - Tape F1084: Human Rights Watch on Mozambique, Undated; 1 (Box 1507)
  - Tapes F1085-F1086: Richard Stengal, author of January Sun; George McGovern, Commission on Independence for Namibia, 1990 April 5; 2 (Box 1508–1509)
- Cultural Tapes, Circa 1979-1991, undated; Series VI
  The series includes tapes with raw footage from the cultural segments of South Africa Now. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved.
  - Tape G1: Sun City, 1985 October 23; 1 (Box 1510)
  - Tape G2: Making of Sun City with Stetsasonic A.F.R.I.C.A., 1 (Box 1511)
  - Tape G3: Miriam Makeba, 1988 February 21; 1 (Box 1512)
  - Tape G4: Music compilation -- Phillip Brooks, 1987 March 16; 1 (Box 1513)
  - Tape G7: Ladysmith Black Mambazo, 1987June; 1 (Box 1514)
  - Tapes G8-G9: Paul Simon's Graceland, Parts I and II, 1988 January 26, February 18; 2 (Box 1515–1516)
  - Tape G10: Film clips, A World Apart, 1988 May 19; 1 (Box 1517)
  - Tape G11: Johnny Clegg video compilation, 1987; 1 (Box 1518)
  - Tape G16: South African music video, Undated; 1 (Box 1519)
  - Tape G17: Info Song (English version), 1987 February 1; 1 (Box 1520)
    The audio on the tape drops off significantly at 4:19.
  - Cry Freedom
    - Tape G18: Clips and trailer, Undated; 1 (Box 1521)
    - Tape G19: Inside story, Undated; 1 (Box 1522)
  - Tapes G20-G23: Freedom Fest, 1-4, 1988 June 11; 4 (Box 1523–1526)
  - Tapes G25-G26: Freedom Beat -- Artists Against Apartheid (A.A.A.) concert, Undated; 2 (Box 1527–1528)
  - Tapes G27: Freedom Beat, 1988; 1 (Box 1529)
  - Tapes G28-G31, G33: Central Park Disarmament Concert, 1988 June 16; 5 (Box 1530–1534)
  - Tape G34: Wembley (Mandela Concert), Undated; 1 (Box 1535)
  - Youssou N'Dour
    - Tape G35: Central Park, Undated; 1 (Box 1536)
    - Tape G36: Audio, Undated; 1 (Box 1537)
  - Tape G37: Segopotso -- Remembrance, Undated; 1 (Box 1538)
  - Tape G38: ICA Artists video tribute to Nelson Mandela, Undated; 1 (Box 1539)
  - Tape G39: Sakhile video (Afravision), Undated; 1 (Box 1540)
  - Tape G40: Saturday Night at the Palace, 1988 May 20; 1 (Box 1541)
  - Tape G41: Nelson Mandela's birthday -- Central Park, 1988 July 18; 1 (Box 1542)
  - Tape G42: Cultural program for United Nations (UN), Undated; 1 (Box 1543)
  - Tape G43: Cannon Film electronic press kit -- Powaqqatsi, 1988 May 2; 1 (Box 1544)
  - Tape G44: Mahlatini and the Mahotella Queens, "Thokozila", Undated; 1 (Box 1545)
  - Tapes G45-G46: Sarafina, Undated; 2 (Box 1546–1547)
  - Tapes G47: Mapantsula film -- interviews with producer and star, Undated; 1 (Box 1548)
  - Tapes G48: Turnley video music, Undated; 1 (Box 1549)
  - Tape G49-G50: Turnley 8mm transfers with Boesak; with Rashid, 1988; 2 (Box 1550–1551)
    One of the audio channels contains only static noise on Tape G50 (box 1551).
  - Tapes G51-G53: The Africa Prize for Leadership--Mugabe, 1988 September 15; 3 (Box 1552–1554)
  - Tape G57: We Have Seen Him! Christian Witness in South Africa from Jim Cason, 1988 October 16; 1 (Box 1555)
  - Tape G58: Khotso, Office of Communication, Christian Church, from Jim Cason, 1988 October 16; 2 (Box 1556)
  - Tapes G59-G64: Turnley source tapes, 1988 August 26; 6 (Box 1557–1562)
  - Tape G65: Laurie Anderson and South African musicians, Undated; 1 (Box 1563)
  - Tape G66a-G66b: Mapantsula, Undated; 2 (Box 1564–1565)
  - Tapes G67-G69: Danny Shechter's 8mm transfer from Athens, 1988 September 14; 3 (Box 1566–1568)
  - Tapes G70-G73: WBCN source tapes 1-4, Undated; 4 (Box 1569–1572)
    See also: Tape G76, box 1575.
  - Tapes G74-G75: Mandela concert -- Wembley, 1988 July 18; 2 (Box 1573–1574)
  - Tape G76: WBCN source tape #5, Undated; 1 (Box 1575)
    See also: Tapes G70-G73, boxes 1569-1572.
  - Tape G77: Johnny Clegg on Saturday Night Live, Undated; 1 (Box 1576)
  - Tape G79: Shaka Zulu, selects, Undated; 1 (Box 1577)
  - Tape G80: Amnesty Tour -- documentary footage of Zimbabwe for Ivory Coast, 1988; 1 (Box 1578)
  - Tapes G81-G82: Shaka Zulu, episode 3, 1988 October 1; 2 (Box 1579–1580)
  - Tape G87: Cone Communication "7 Minute Rock Video", Undated; 1 (Box 1581)
  - Tape G89: Cone Communication "Human Rights Now," Amnesty footage, Undated; 1 (Box 1582)
  - Tape G90: Cone Communication "Human Rights Now -- HBO composite reel", Undated; 1 (Box 1583)